<record>
  <isbns></isbns>
  <shortDBName>bsu</shortDBName>
  <isiType>JOUR</isiType>
  <notes></notes>
  <mid>PSS</mid>
  <language>eng</language>
  <source>Journal of Personal Selling &amp;amp; Sales Management</source>
  <bookEdition></bookEdition>
  <title>Using the power of machine learning in sales research: process and potential.</title>
  <pageEnd>194</pageEnd>
  <pageStart>178</pageStart>
  <peerReviewed>true</peerReviewed>
  <isOpenAccess></isOpenAccess>
  <publicationDate>20230901</publicationDate>
  <pageCount>17</pageCount>
  <publisherLocations></publisherLocations>
  <issue>3</issue>
  <identifiers></identifiers>
  <subjects>Data mining ; Machine learning ; Research questions ; Statistical learning</subjects>
  <abstract>This study addresses the potential for improving the accuracy, scope, and value of sales research through the application of data mining and machine learning algorithms. By examining prior research, identifying opportunities for improvement, and assessing gaps that can benefit from machine learning, research and application are made more accessible for sales researchers and managers. Machine learning can address important sales research questions that cannot be answered with the same accuracy or efficiency as traditional research methods. This study demonstrates the benefits of the methods through an example of application to the prediction of salesforce performance based on behavioral, attitudinal, and demographic data. This includes future research ideas, usage cases, and applications where machine learning could advance sales research and management. Machine learning and predictive analytics methods have multiple applications, including in B2C and B2B market contexts and for companies and independent sales teams.</abstract>
  <pubTypes>Academic Journal</pubTypes>
  <an>171107137</an>
  <docTypes>Article</docTypes>
  <volume>43</volume>
  <issns>0885-3134</issns>
  <degreeLevel></degreeLevel>
  <plink>https://research.ebsco.com/linkprocessor/plink?id=54661cf6-d2a7-3559-9b85-5de793959cc5</plink>
  <doids></doids>
  <publisher>Taylor &amp;amp; Francis Ltd</publisher>
  <contributors>Glackin, Caroline E. W. ; Adivar, Murat</contributors>
  <coverDate>Sep2023</coverDate>
  <longDBName>Business Source Ultimate</longDBName>
  <doi>10.1080/08853134.2022.2128812</doi>
</record>
