<record>
  <isbns></isbns>
  <shortDBName>cmedm</shortDBName>
  <isiType>JOUR</isiType>
  <notes></notes>
  <mid></mid>
  <language>eng</language>
  <source>Advanced science (Weinheim, Baden-Wurttemberg, Germany)</source>
  <bookEdition></bookEdition>
  <title>Machine Learning Techniques for Simulating Human Psychophysical Testing of Low-Resolution Phosphene Face Images in Artificial Vision.</title>
  <pageEnd></pageEnd>
  <pageStart>e2405789</pageStart>
  <peerReviewed>true</peerReviewed>
  <isOpenAccess></isOpenAccess>
  <publicationDate>20250401</publicationDate>
  <pageCount></pageCount>
  <publisherLocations>Germany</publisherLocations>
  <issue>15</issue>
  <identifiers></identifiers>
  <subjects>Machine Learning ; Phosphenes physiology ; Psychophysics methods ; Facial Recognition physiology ; Humans ; Female ; Male ; Adult</subjects>
  <abstract>To evaluate the quality of artificial visual percepts generated by emerging methodologies, researchers often rely on labor-intensive and tedious human psychophysical experiments. These experiments necessitate repeated iterations upon any major/minor modifications in the hardware/software configurations. Here, the capacity of standard machine learning (ML) models is investigated to accurately replicate quaternary match-to-sample tasks using low-resolution facial images represented by arrays of phosphenes as input stimuli. Initially, the performance of the ML models trained to approximate innate human facial recognition abilities across a dataset comprising 3600 phosphene images of human faces is analyzed. Subsequently, due to the time constraints and the potential for subject fatigue, the psychophysical test is limited to presenting only 720 low-resolution phosphene images to 36 human subjects. Notably, the superior model adeptly mirrors the behavioral trend of human subjects, offering precise predictions for 8 out of 9 phosphene quality levels on the overlapping test queries. Subsequently, human recognition performances for untested phosphene images are predicted, streamlining the process and minimizing the need for additional psychophysical tests. The findings underscore the transformative potential of ML in reshaping the research paradigm of visual prosthetics, facilitating the expedited advancement of prostheses.</abstract>
  <pubTypes>Journal Article ; Academic Journal</pubTypes>
  <an>39985243</an>
  <docTypes>Journal Article</docTypes>
  <volume>12</volume>
  <issns>2198-3844 ; Electronic</issns>
  <degreeLevel></degreeLevel>
  <plink>https://research.ebsco.com/linkprocessor/plink?id=de77cc47-c60b-3d61-bb6b-a2ae26c239fd</plink>
  <doids></doids>
  <publisher>WILEY-VCH</publisher>
  <contributors>An, Na Min ; Roh, Hyeonhee ; Kim, Sein ; Kim, Jae Hun ; Im, Maesoon</contributors>
  <coverDate>2025 Apr</coverDate>
  <longDBName>MEDLINE</longDBName>
  <doi>10.1002/advs.202405789</doi>
</record>
