<record>
  <isbns></isbns>
  <shortDBName>bsu</shortDBName>
  <isiType>JOUR</isiType>
  <notes></notes>
  <mid>HAYR</mid>
  <language>eng</language>
  <source>Ingénierie des Systèmes d'Information</source>
  <bookEdition></bookEdition>
  <title>An Audio Feature Extraction Approach Using Machine Learning for Spoken Audio File Indexing.</title>
  <pageEnd>770</pageEnd>
  <pageStart>763</pageStart>
  <peerReviewed>true</peerReviewed>
  <isOpenAccess></isOpenAccess>
  <publicationDate>20250301</publicationDate>
  <pageCount>8</pageCount>
  <publisherLocations></publisherLocations>
  <issue>3</issue>
  <identifiers></identifiers>
  <subjects>Data mining ; Artificial neural networks ; Machine learning ; Speech processing systems ; Heuristic algorithms ; Wavelets (Mathematics)</subjects>
  <abstract>With the rise of voice and audio data processing, data mining now enables the automatic extraction of hidden knowledge from vast datasets, particularly in speech processing and spoken language dialogue. In light of the growing volume of voice data generated by applications such as e-learning and e-conferences, data warehouses hold a substantial amount of audio data requiring efficient indexing. However, traditional algorithms struggle to handle the specificities of such voice data. This work proposed a novel extraction approach leveraging heuristic algorithms based on original descriptors obtained through wavelet analysis, an audio feature engineering process, and an autoencoder for selecting relevant descriptors. We extracted 119 descriptors from 1,000 audio files in the GTZAN database. After the extraction phase, we used machine learning in the encoder's latent space to select 80 relevant descriptors that preserve the semantic meaning of the files. We evaluated the effectiveness of our approach using a multilayer perceptron. The neural network achieved an accuracy of 87.5% compared to 77.8% reported in the literature.</abstract>
  <pubTypes>Academic Journal</pubTypes>
  <an>184436900</an>
  <docTypes>Article</docTypes>
  <volume>30</volume>
  <issns>1633-1311</issns>
  <degreeLevel></degreeLevel>
  <plink>https://research.ebsco.com/linkprocessor/plink?id=43da3462-29ae-322f-ae82-5c95c23f90fc</plink>
  <doids></doids>
  <publisher>International Information &amp;amp; Engineering Technology Association (IIETA)</publisher>
  <contributors>Koua, Hortense N'dri ; Brou, Marcellin Koua ; Gnagne, Maxime Seraphin</contributors>
  <coverDate>Mar2025</coverDate>
  <longDBName>Business Source Ultimate</longDBName>
  <doi>10.18280/isi.300320</doi>
</record>
