<record>
  <isbns></isbns>
  <shortDBName>bsu</shortDBName>
  <isiType>JOUR</isiType>
  <notes></notes>
  <mid>B95</mid>
  <language>eng</language>
  <source>International Journal of Production Research</source>
  <bookEdition></bookEdition>
  <title>Novelty detection framework for monitoring connected vehicle systems with imperfect data.</title>
  <pageEnd>14</pageEnd>
  <pageStart>1</pageStart>
  <peerReviewed>true</peerReviewed>
  <isOpenAccess></isOpenAccess>
  <publicationDate>20250328</publicationDate>
  <pageCount>14</pageCount>
  <publisherLocations></publisherLocations>
  <issue></issue>
  <identifiers></identifiers>
  <subjects>Commercial vehicles ; New product development ; Automobile and Other Motor Vehicle Merchant Wholesalers ; Motor Vehicle Supplies and New Parts Merchant Wholesalers ; Recreational and other motor vehicles merchant wholesalers ; Marketing Consulting Services ; Ensemble learning ; Machine learning ; Motor vehicles</subjects>
  <abstract>Shrinking product development cycles and increasing vehicle complexities necessitate a new generation of monitoring and diagnostic algorithms that can demonstrate increased autonomy and adaptivity. Conventional approaches, which make strict assumptions about data fidelity and failure ground-truth availability, face challenges in modern connected vehicle applications. This paper proposes a novelty detection-based autonomous monitoring framework that flags anomalies under sparse and noisy data with limited or no access to ground-truth information. The framework proposes an optional mechanism for extracting age-degrading features and offers a robust approach for fusing the output of heterogeneous novelty detectors to determine the health state of target components. We validate the proposed framework using connected vehicle data for 12-volt battery systems employed by a large fleet of commercial vehicles of a global automotive manufacturer. To demonstrate versatility, we also tested the framework on bench-testing data from LFP/graphite battery cells. Results demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed framework.</abstract>
  <pubTypes>Academic Journal</pubTypes>
  <an>184061816</an>
  <docTypes>Article</docTypes>
  <volume></volume>
  <issns>0020-7543</issns>
  <degreeLevel></degreeLevel>
  <plink>https://research.ebsco.com/linkprocessor/plink?id=f3f890a5-6165-36dd-9f1d-4239c6e65664</plink>
  <doids></doids>
  <publisher>Taylor &amp;amp; Francis Ltd</publisher>
  <contributors>Badfar, M. ; Yildirim, M. ; Chinnam, R.B.</contributors>
  <coverDate>Mar2025</coverDate>
  <longDBName>Business Source Ultimate</longDBName>
  <doi>10.1080/00207543.2025.2484320</doi>
</record>
