<record>
  <isbns></isbns>
  <shortDBName>edssch</shortDBName>
  <isiType>GEN</isiType>
  <notes></notes>
  <mid></mid>
  <language></language>
  <source>Annals of Surgery Open</source>
  <bookEdition></bookEdition>
  <title>Development and Validation of a Machine Learning Prediction Model for Textbook Outcome in Liver Surgery: Results From a Multicenter, International Cohort.</title>
  <pageEnd></pageEnd>
  <pageStart></pageStart>
  <peerReviewed></peerReviewed>
  <isOpenAccess></isOpenAccess>
  <publicationDate>20250301</publicationDate>
  <pageCount></pageCount>
  <publisherLocations></publisherLocations>
  <issue>1</issue>
  <identifiers></identifiers>
  <subjects>hepatectomy ; liver surgery ; machine learning ; prediction model ; textbook outcome</subjects>
  <abstract>OBJECTIVE: This study aimed to (1) develop a machine learning (ML) model that predicts the textbook outcome in liver surgery (TOLS) using preoperative variables and (2) validate the TOLS criteria by determining whether TOLS is associated with long-term survival after hepatectomy. BACKGROUND: Textbook outcome is a composite measure that combines several favorable outcomes into a single metric and represents the optimal postoperative course. Recently, an expert panel of surgeons proposed a Delphi consensus-based definition of TOLS. METHODS: Adult patients who underwent hepatectomies were identified from a multicenter, international cohort (2010-2022). After data preprocessing and train-test splitting (80:20), 4 models for predicting TOLS were trained and tested. Following model optimization, the performance of the models was evaluated using receiver operating characteristic curves, and a web-based calculator was developed. In addition, a multivariable Cox proportional hazards analysis was conducted to determine the association between TOLS and overall survival (OS). RESULTS: A total of 2059 patients were included, with 62.8% meeting the criteria for TOLS. The XGBoost model, which had the best performance with an area under the curve of 0.73, was chosen for the web-based calculator. The most predictive variables for having TOLS were a minimally invasive approach, fewer lesions, lower Charlson Comorbidity Index, lower preoperative creatinine levels, and smaller lesions. In the multivariable analysis, having TOLS was associated with improved OS (hazard ratio = 0.82, P = 0.015). CONCLUSIONS: Our ML model can predict TOLS with acceptable discrimination. We validated the TOLS criteria by demonstrating a significant association with improved OS, thus supporting their use in informing patient care.</abstract>
  <pubTypes>Academic Journal</pubTypes>
  <an>edssch.oai:escholarship.org:ark:/13030/qt6c49j8p8</an>
  <docTypes>article</docTypes>
  <volume>6</volume>
  <issns></issns>
  <degreeLevel></degreeLevel>
  <plink>https://research.ebsco.com/linkprocessor/plink?id=19c4275f-96e8-3c9d-ac8b-d3cafc1f9e68</plink>
  <doids></doids>
  <publisher>eScholarship, University of California</publisher>
  <contributors>Wang, Jane ; Ashraf Ganjouei, Amir ; Hibi, Taizo ; Lluis, Nuria ; Gomes, Camilla ; Romero-Hernandez, Fernanda ; Yin, Han ; Calthorpe, Lucia ; Okamura, Yukiyasu ; Abe, Yuta ; Tanaka, Shogo ; Tanabe, Minoru ; Morise, Zeniche ; Asbun, Horacio ; Geller, David ; Abu Hilal, Mohammed ; Adam, Mohamed ; Alseidi, Adnan</contributors>
  <coverDate>2025</coverDate>
  <longDBName>eScholarship</longDBName>
  <doi></doi>
</record>
