<record>
  <isbns></isbns>
  <shortDBName>bsu</shortDBName>
  <isiType>JOUR</isiType>
  <notes></notes>
  <mid>3BXV</mid>
  <language>chi</language>
  <source>Journal of China University of Petroleum</source>
  <bookEdition></bookEdition>
  <title>基于集成机器学习模型的混合原油凝点预测方法.</title>
  <pageEnd>222</pageEnd>
  <pageStart>214</pageStart>
  <peerReviewed>true</peerReviewed>
  <isOpenAccess></isOpenAccess>
  <publicationDate>20250401</publicationDate>
  <pageCount>9</pageCount>
  <publisherLocations></publisherLocations>
  <issue>2</issue>
  <identifiers></identifiers>
  <subjects>Petroleum Bulk Stations and Terminals ; Crude Petroleum and Natural Gas Extraction ; Petroleum and Petroleum Products Merchant Wholesalers (except Bulk Stations and Terminals) ; Pipeline Transportation of Crude Oil ; Petroleum and petroleum products merchant wholesalers ; Pipeline Transportation of Refined Petroleum Products ; Oil and Gas Pipeline and Related Structures Construction ; Machine learning ; Petroleum ; Petroleum distribution ; Petroleum pipelines ; Prediction models</subjects>
  <abstract>Mixed transport is the most common way to transport multiple crude oil in the same pipeline. Grasping the flow properties of the mixed oil quickly and accurately is the basis of making the mixed crude oil distribution scheme and ensuring the safe, efficient and flexible operation of the pipeline. The gel point of mixed crude oil is often determined by the manual sampling test, so it is difficult to effectively control the crude oil into the pipeline in time. It is simple and easy to calculate the gel point of mixed crude oil by using the empirical model based on the ratio and gel point of component crude oil, but there is a bottleneck in the method to improve the prediction accuracy. An integrated machine learning model based on XG-Boost was proposed to predict the gel point of mixed crude oil. The results show that, with the inputs of gel point, density, viscosity and ratio in component oils, the mean absolute error of the model prediction estimations after training with 8912 data is 1. 12 ℃ . When the gel point of the component crude oil is missing, the mean absolute error is 1. 93 ℃ and the percentage of the predicted absolute error within 2 ℃ is 88. 0%.</abstract>
  <pubTypes>Academic Journal</pubTypes>
  <an>184531209</an>
  <docTypes>Article</docTypes>
  <volume>49</volume>
  <issns>1673-5005</issns>
  <degreeLevel></degreeLevel>
  <plink>https://research.ebsco.com/linkprocessor/plink?id=83183569-9402-3a0b-86f2-fea106611cb0</plink>
  <doids></doids>
  <publisher>China University of Petroleum</publisher>
  <contributors>何宇轩 ; 苏 怀 ; 张 成 ; 苏 杨 ; 李鸿英 ; 黄 骞 ; 张劲军</contributors>
  <coverDate>Apr2025</coverDate>
  <longDBName>Business Source Ultimate</longDBName>
  <doi>10.3969/j.issn.1673-5005.2025.02.021</doi>
</record>
