<record>
  <isbns></isbns>
  <shortDBName>bsu</shortDBName>
  <isiType>JOUR</isiType>
  <notes></notes>
  <mid>NEPO</mid>
  <language>per</language>
  <source>Business Intelligence Management Studies</source>
  <bookEdition></bookEdition>
  <title>ارائه مدل پیامدهای کاربرد هوش مصنوعی و یادگیری ماشین در تبلیغات و فروش</title>
  <pageEnd>270</pageEnd>
  <pageStart>223</pageStart>
  <peerReviewed>true</peerReviewed>
  <isOpenAccess></isOpenAccess>
  <publicationDate>20240701</publicationDate>
  <pageCount>48</pageCount>
  <publisherLocations></publisherLocations>
  <issue>48</issue>
  <identifiers></identifiers>
  <subjects>Artificial intelligence ; Advertising agencies ; Advertising Agencies ; Machine learning ; Digital technology ; Rank correlation (Statistics) ; Snowball sampling</subjects>
  <abstract>The digital world provides many opportunities for marketers to reach customers. However, in the fast-paced world, finding new and innovative ways to advertise and sell products and services is very important. Due to the advancement of artificial intelligence and its development in the field of advertising and sales, professionals now have the tools to completely redefine the current understanding of branding, marketing, advertising and sales. The growing popularity of the Internet and the increased use of mobile devices are generating massive amounts of consumer data that feed artificial intelligence-based systems. This research is a type of mixed research with a qualitative and quantitative approach, which is a survey descriptive study in terms of its purpose, application, and in terms of data collection. The statistical population of the research was managers and experts in the field of digital marketing and IT in the field of advertising and sales, who were selected using the snowball sampling method. In the qualitative part, the tools for collecting information were library and articles review, interviews, and in the quantitative part, questionnaires. In the qualitative part of the data analysis method, using the theme analysis that was compiled with MAXQDA software and using the coding method, and in the quantitative part, the analysis method was based on Kendall's correlation test. According to the results of the research, 7 main themes, 22 sub-themes and 44 codes were discovered, which included the consequences of using artificial intelligence and machine learning in advertising and sales. The findings of the research can have important results for marketers and activists in the field of advertising and sales. Among the consequences of the application of artificial intelligence and machine learning, we can mention things such as understanding, recognizing and revealing consumer needs and desires, classifying target advertisements, intelligent evolution of commercial advertisements, innovation in sales, development of sales channels, and optimization of the fields of using artificial intelligence in advertising agencies Keywords:: artificial intelligence, machine learning, big data, advertising and sales.</abstract>
  <pubTypes>Academic Journal</pubTypes>
  <an>179007273</an>
  <docTypes>Article</docTypes>
  <volume>12</volume>
  <issns>2821-0964</issns>
  <degreeLevel></degreeLevel>
  <plink>https://research.ebsco.com/linkprocessor/plink?id=d9af1a9a-bfc5-347c-9e54-95bfa3f68a11</plink>
  <doids></doids>
  <publisher>Allameh Tabatabai University</publisher>
  <contributors>حسین رحیمی کلور ; رحیم محمدخانی</contributors>
  <coverDate>Summer2024</coverDate>
  <longDBName>Business Source Ultimate</longDBName>
  <doi>10.22054/ims.2024.76711.2403</doi>
</record>
