<record>
  <isbns></isbns>
  <shortDBName>edsarx</shortDBName>
  <isiType>GEN</isiType>
  <notes></notes>
  <mid></mid>
  <language></language>
  <source></source>
  <bookEdition></bookEdition>
  <title>Machine Learning-assisted High-speed Combinatorial Optimization with Ising Machines for Dynamically Changing Problems</title>
  <pageEnd></pageEnd>
  <pageStart></pageStart>
  <peerReviewed></peerReviewed>
  <isOpenAccess></isOpenAccess>
  <publicationDate>20250331</publicationDate>
  <pageCount></pageCount>
  <publisherLocations></publisherLocations>
  <issue></issue>
  <identifiers></identifiers>
  <subjects>Computer Science - Emerging Technologies ; Computer Science - Machine Learning</subjects>
  <abstract>Quantum or quantum-inspired Ising machines have recently shown promise in solving combinatorial optimization problems in a short time. Real-world applications, such as time division multiple access (TDMA) scheduling for wireless multi-hop networks and financial trading, require solving those problems sequentially where the size and characteristics change dynamically. However, using Ising machines involves challenges to shorten system-wide latency due to the transfer of large Ising model or the cloud access and to determine the parameters for each problem. Here we show a combinatorial optimization method using embedded Ising machines, which enables solving diverse problems at high speed without runtime parameter tuning. We customize the algorithm and circuit architecture of the simulated bifurcation-based Ising machine to compress the Ising model and accelerate computation and then built a machine learning model to estimate appropriate parameters using extensive training data. In TDMA scheduling for wireless multi-hop networks, our demonstration has shown that the sophisticated system can adapt to changes in the problem and showed that it has a speed advantage over conventional methods.</abstract>
  <pubTypes>Working Paper</pubTypes>
  <an>edsarx.2503.23966</an>
  <docTypes>Working Paper</docTypes>
  <volume></volume>
  <issns></issns>
  <degreeLevel></degreeLevel>
  <plink>https://research.ebsco.com/linkprocessor/plink?id=33717e38-a06a-3f3b-b036-744542fd35a9</plink>
  <doids></doids>
  <publisher></publisher>
  <contributors>Hamakawa, Yohei ; Kashimata, Tomoya ; Yamasaki, Masaya ; Tatsumura, Kosuke</contributors>
  <coverDate>20250331</coverDate>
  <longDBName>arXiv</longDBName>
  <doi></doi>
</record>
