<record>
  <isbns></isbns>
  <shortDBName>8gh</shortDBName>
  <isiType>JOUR</isiType>
  <notes></notes>
  <mid>B86R</mid>
  <language>eng</language>
  <source>Journal of Geophysical Research. Atmospheres</source>
  <bookEdition></bookEdition>
  <title>Improvement of Summer Precipitation Simulation Over the Tibetan Plateau: Implications for Assimilating Pseudo Soundings Generated by Machine Learning.</title>
  <pageEnd>17</pageEnd>
  <pageStart>1</pageStart>
  <peerReviewed>true</peerReviewed>
  <isOpenAccess></isOpenAccess>
  <publicationDate>20250328</publicationDate>
  <pageCount>17</pageCount>
  <publisherLocations></publisherLocations>
  <issue>6</issue>
  <identifiers></identifiers>
  <subjects>Random forest algorithms ; Machine learning ; Atmospheric boundary layer ; Data assimilation ; Atmospheric models</subjects>
  <abstract>Due to the sparse observations over the Tibetan Plateau (TP), initial conditions in atmospheric models over the TP have large uncertainty, which could degrade the simulation performance of precipitation over the TP. This study proposes a novel approach for generating "pseudo soundings" for the atmospheric model's initial conditions. In each "pseudo soundings", the vertical profiles of heat and moisture are estimated by a random forest algorithm from the evolution and mean state of precursor convective precipitation. Results indicate that the vertical structures of temperature and humidity in "pseudo soundings" estimated in this study could be superior to the reanalysis data set, and could well remedy the insufficient heat and moisture information for model's initial condition over the TP where in situ conventional soundings are absent. Compared to the ERA5 reanalysis data set, the mean relative error of temperature and specific humidity estimated in this study could be reduced by 0.7% and 5.7%, respectively. Verification based on a series of simulations illustrates that assimilating vertical profiles of heat and moisture in "pseudo soundings" would alleviate the spurious and overestimated summer precipitation in simulations over the TP. The mean simulation bias of hourly precipitation could be reduced by 31.8%, compared to assimilating in situ conventional soundings only. Further investigations suggest that assimilating vertical profiles of heat and moisture in "pseudo soundings" would improve the simulation performance of summer precipitation by producing a dryer and more convective stable lower atmosphere over the TP. Plain Language Summary: Improving simulation performance of precipitation over the Tibetan Plateau (TP) is a challenging issue, because reliable vertical profiles of heat and moisture over the TP are insufficient, which could degrade initial conditions in atmospheric models. In this study, we proposed an approach to estimate vertical profiles of heat and moisture from the evolution and mean state of precursor convective precipitation, using a machine learning algorithm. We demonstrate that the vertical structures of temperature and humidity estimated in this study could be superior to the reanalysis data set over the TP. Assimilating vertical profiles of heat and moisture estimated in this study would improve summer precipitation simulation over the TP. These results may be of use in regional model development and theoretical analysis of data assimilation research, especially over the regions with sparse observations. Key Points: A novel method, which estimates heat and moisture profiles from precursor convective precipitation evolution, is proposedThe vertical structures of heat and moisture over the Tibetan Plateau estimated in this study could be superior to the reanalysis data setAssimilating the estimated heat and moisture profiles would obviously improve summer precipitation simulation over the Tibetan Plateau</abstract>
  <pubTypes>Academic Journal</pubTypes>
  <an>184109394</an>
  <docTypes>Article</docTypes>
  <volume>130</volume>
  <issns>2169-897X</issns>
  <degreeLevel></degreeLevel>
  <plink>https://research.ebsco.com/linkprocessor/plink?id=87d538a7-f355-32c1-91dc-e79eaf94062b</plink>
  <doids></doids>
  <publisher>Wiley-Blackwell</publisher>
  <contributors>Zhang, Feimin ; Cui, Hao ; Wang, Hao</contributors>
  <coverDate>3/28/2025</coverDate>
  <longDBName>GreenFILE</longDBName>
  <doi>10.1029/2024JD042551</doi>
</record>
