<record>
  <isbns>9781643684468 ; 9781643684475</isbns>
  <shortDBName>e000xww</shortDBName>
  <isiType>BOOK</isiType>
  <notes></notes>
  <mid></mid>
  <language>eng</language>
  <source>Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence and Applications</source>
  <bookEdition></bookEdition>
  <title>Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence : Proceedings of MLIS 2023</title>
  <pageEnd></pageEnd>
  <pageStart></pageStart>
  <peerReviewed></peerReviewed>
  <isOpenAccess></isOpenAccess>
  <publicationDate>20230101</publicationDate>
  <pageCount></pageCount>
  <publisherLocations>Amsterdam</publisherLocations>
  <issue></issue>
  <identifiers></identifiers>
  <subjects>COMPUTERS / Artificial Intelligence / General ; Machine learning--Congresses ; Artificial intelligence--Congresses</subjects>
  <abstract>Machine learning (ML) and intelligent systems are now comprehensively applied for the solving of practical problems. Emerging techniques such as big data analysis, deep neural networks, AI, and IoT have been adopted and integrated into the development and application of machine learning and intelligent systems, and their wide application in industry, medicine, engineering, education and other mainstream domains have made them a part of everyday life. This book presents the proceedings of MLIS 2023, the 5th International Conference on Machine Learning and Intelligent Systems, held as a hybrid event from 17-20 November 2023 in Macau, China. This annual conference aims to provide a platform for a knowledge exchange of the most recent scientific and technological advances in the field of ML and intelligent systems, and to strengthen links within the scientific community in related research areas. A total of 80 submissions were received for the conference, of which 20 papers were selected for presentation and publication in these proceedings following a rigorous peer-review process. Papers were assessed on originality, scientific/practical significance, compelling logical reasoning and language, and the selected papers cover a wide range of topics, and provide innovative and original ideas or results of general significance in the field of ML and intelligent systems. Providing a current overview of developments in the fields of machine learning and intelligent systems, the book will be of interest to all those working in this field.</abstract>
  <pubTypes>eBook</pubTypes>
  <an>3732286</an>
  <docTypes>eBook</docTypes>
  <volume>00374</volume>
  <issns></issns>
  <degreeLevel></degreeLevel>
  <plink>https://research.ebsco.com/linkprocessor/plink?id=871ff069-fcae-34ae-bc48-c6952b4853c9</plink>
  <doids>NL$3732286$PDF</doids>
  <publisher>SAGE Publications Ltd</publisher>
  <contributors>J.-L. Kim</contributors>
  <coverDate>2023</coverDate>
  <longDBName>eBook Academic Collection (EBSCOhost)</longDBName>
  <doi></doi>
</record>
