<record>
  <isbns></isbns>
  <shortDBName>edsarx</shortDBName>
  <isiType>GEN</isiType>
  <notes></notes>
  <mid></mid>
  <language></language>
  <source></source>
  <bookEdition></bookEdition>
  <title>Computational, Data-Driven, and Physics-Informed Machine Learning Approaches for Microstructure Modeling in Metal Additive Manufacturing</title>
  <pageEnd></pageEnd>
  <pageStart></pageStart>
  <peerReviewed></peerReviewed>
  <isOpenAccess></isOpenAccess>
  <publicationDate>20250502</publicationDate>
  <pageCount></pageCount>
  <publisherLocations></publisherLocations>
  <issue></issue>
  <identifiers></identifiers>
  <subjects>Computer Science - Machine Learning</subjects>
  <abstract>Metal additive manufacturing enables unprecedented design freedom and the production of customized, complex components. However, the rapid melting and solidification dynamics inherent to metal AM processes generate heterogeneous, non-equilibrium microstructures that significantly impact mechanical properties and subsequent functionality. Predicting microstructure and its evolution across spatial and temporal scales remains a central challenge for process optimization and defect mitigation. While conventional experimental techniques and physics-based simulations provide a physical foundation and valuable insights, they face critical limitations. In contrast, data-driven machine learning offers an alternative prediction approach and powerful pattern recognition but often operate as black-box, lacking generalizability and physical consistency. To overcome these limitations, physics-informed machine learning, including physics-informed neural networks, has emerged as a promising paradigm by embedding governing physical laws into neural network architectures, thereby enhancing accuracy, transparency, data efficiency, and extrapolation capabilities. This work presents a comprehensive evaluation of modeling strategies for microstructure prediction in metal AM. The strengths and limitations of experimental, computational, and data-driven methods are analyzed in depth, and highlight recent advances in hybrid PIML frameworks that integrate physical knowledge with ML. Key challenges, such as data scarcity, multi-scale coupling, and uncertainty quantification, are discussed alongside future directions. Ultimately, this assessment underscores the importance of PIML-based hybrid approaches in enabling predictive, scalable, and physically consistent microstructure modeling for site-specific, microstructure-aware process control and the reliable production of high-performance AM components.</abstract>
  <pubTypes>Working Paper</pubTypes>
  <an>edsarx.2505.01424</an>
  <docTypes>Working Paper</docTypes>
  <volume></volume>
  <issns></issns>
  <degreeLevel></degreeLevel>
  <plink>https://research.ebsco.com/linkprocessor/plink?id=ddd2de0d-8144-3c6d-b2ab-a5799e290843</plink>
  <doids></doids>
  <publisher></publisher>
  <contributors>Patel, D. ; Sharma, R. ; Guo, Y. B.</contributors>
  <coverDate>20250502</coverDate>
  <longDBName>arXiv</longDBName>
  <doi></doi>
</record>
