<record>
  <isbns></isbns>
  <shortDBName>cmedm</shortDBName>
  <isiType>JOUR</isiType>
  <notes></notes>
  <mid></mid>
  <language>eng</language>
  <source>BMC health services research</source>
  <bookEdition></bookEdition>
  <title>Predicting total healthcare demand using machine learning: separate and combined analysis of predisposing, enabling, and need factors.</title>
  <pageEnd></pageEnd>
  <pageStart>366</pageStart>
  <peerReviewed>true</peerReviewed>
  <isOpenAccess></isOpenAccess>
  <publicationDate>20250312</publicationDate>
  <pageCount></pageCount>
  <publisherLocations>England</publisherLocations>
  <issue>1</issue>
  <identifiers></identifiers>
  <subjects>Turkey ; Machine Learning ; Humans ; Male ; Female ; Middle Aged ; Adult ; Turkey ; Health Services Needs and Demand ; Aged ; Adolescent ; Logistic Models ; Young Adult ; Health Surveys ; Patient Acceptance of Health Care statistics &amp;amp; numerical data</subjects>
  <abstract>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The data utilized in this study are secondary in nature, sourced from the Turkish Health Survey micro datasets provided by the Turkish Statistical Institute (TÜİK). These datasets are made accessible to researchers upon request and payment of a specified fee. As the data are anonymized, no personally identifiable information is disclosed, ensuring participant confidentiality. Consequently, this study was conducted using an already publicly accessible secondary dataset, and no additional consent or ethical approval was required. This approach is consistent with prior studies using older versions of the same dataset [79], where no additional research permission or ethical committee approval was necessary for generating scientific outputs. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</abstract>
  <pubTypes>Journal Article ; Academic Journal</pubTypes>
  <an>40075408</an>
  <docTypes>Journal Article</docTypes>
  <volume>25</volume>
  <issns>1472-6963 ; Electronic</issns>
  <degreeLevel></degreeLevel>
  <plink>https://research.ebsco.com/linkprocessor/plink?id=831eff88-fcd6-3cff-90c2-78521e23ea2e</plink>
  <doids></doids>
  <publisher>BioMed Central</publisher>
  <contributors>Orhan, Fatih ; Kurutkan, Mehmet Nurullah</contributors>
  <coverDate>2025 Mar 12</coverDate>
  <longDBName>MEDLINE</longDBName>
  <doi>10.1186/s12913-025-12502-5</doi>
</record>
