<record>
  <isbns></isbns>
  <shortDBName>eric</shortDBName>
  <isiType>JOUR</isiType>
  <notes></notes>
  <mid></mid>
  <language>eng</language>
  <source>Informatics in Education</source>
  <bookEdition></bookEdition>
  <title>Data Science and Machine Learning Teaching Practices with Focus on Vocational Education and Training</title>
  <pageEnd>690</pageEnd>
  <pageStart>671</pageStart>
  <peerReviewed>true</peerReviewed>
  <isOpenAccess></isOpenAccess>
  <publicationDate>20230101</publicationDate>
  <pageCount>20</pageCount>
  <publisherLocations></publisherLocations>
  <issue>4</issue>
  <identifiers></identifiers>
  <subjects>Data Science ; Artificial Intelligence ; Man Machine Systems ; Vocational Education ; Labor Market ; Job Skills ; Global Approach ; High Schools ; Universities ; Foreign Countries ; Education Work Relationship ; Educational Practices ; Slovenia ; Serbia ; Macedonia</subjects>
  <abstract>With the development of technology allowing for a rapid expansion of data science and machine learning in our everyday lives, a significant gap is forming in the global job market where the demand for qualified workers in these fields cannot be properly satisfied. This worrying trend calls for an immediate action in education, where these skills must be taught to students at all levels in an efficient and up-to-date manner. This paper gives an overview of the current state of data science and machine learning education globally and both at the high school and university levels, while outlining some illustrative and positive examples. Special focus is given to vocational education and training (VET), where the teaching of these skills is at its very beginning. Also presented and analysed are survey results concerning VET students in Slovenia, Serbia, and North Macedonia, and their knowledge, interests, and prerequisites regarding data science and machine learning. These results confirm the need for development of efficient and accessible curricula and courses on these subjects in vocational schools.</abstract>
  <pubTypes>Academic Journal</pubTypes>
  <an>EJ1410494</an>
  <docTypes>Journal Articles ; Reports - Research</docTypes>
  <volume>22</volume>
  <issns>1648-5831 ; 2335-8971</issns>
  <degreeLevel></degreeLevel>
  <plink>https://research.ebsco.com/linkprocessor/plink?id=397f72da-c8e6-32fe-9fae-5506e3a92a2e</plink>
  <doids></doids>
  <publisher></publisher>
  <contributors>Gorjan Nadzinski ; Branislav Gerazov ; Stefan Zlatinov ; Tomislav Kartalov ; Marija Markovska Dimitrovska ; Hristijan Gjoreski ; Risto Chavdarov ; Zivko Kokolanski ; Igor Atanasov ; Jelena Horstmann ; Uros Sterle ; Matjaz Gams</contributors>
  <coverDate>2023</coverDate>
  <longDBName>ERIC</longDBName>
  <doi></doi>
</record>
