<record>
  <isbns></isbns>
  <shortDBName>8gh</shortDBName>
  <isiType>JOUR</isiType>
  <notes></notes>
  <mid>B86U</mid>
  <language>eng</language>
  <source>Journal of Geophysical Research. Planets</source>
  <bookEdition></bookEdition>
  <title>WindSightNet: The Inter‐Annual Variability of Martian Winds Retrieved From InSight's Seismic Data With Machine Learning.</title>
  <pageEnd>24</pageEnd>
  <pageStart>1</pageStart>
  <peerReviewed>true</peerReviewed>
  <isOpenAccess></isOpenAccess>
  <publicationDate>20250201</publicationDate>
  <pageCount>24</pageCount>
  <publisherLocations></publisherLocations>
  <issue>2</issue>
  <identifiers></identifiers>
  <subjects>Dust ; Machine learning ; Wind speed measurement ; Atmospheric boundary layer ; Atmospheric models</subjects>
  <abstract>Wind measurements from landed missions on Mars are vital to characterize the near surface atmospheric behavior on Mars and improve atmospheric models. These winds are responsible for aeolian change and the mixing of dust in and out of the atmosphere, which has a significant effect on global circulation. The NASA InSight mission recorded wind data for around 750 sols. The seismometer, however, recorded data for around 1400 sols. The dominant source of energy in the seismic data is in fact due to winds. To this end, we propose a machine learning model, dubbed WindSightNet, to map the seismic data to wind speed and direction. The trained network achieves wind speed and direction measurements with errors of 0.932 m/s and 32.6°. We use WindSightNet to retrieve winds from the entire time the seismometer was recording to compare year‐to‐year wind variations at InSight. The continuous nature of the data set enables the extraction of periodic behavior. We observe a pattern of waves due to baroclinic activity with periods of ∼ ${\sim} $2–3, ∼ ${\sim} $4, ∼ ${\sim} $5–7 and ∼ ${\sim} $9–20 sols occurring Ls= ${L}_{s}=$180–360°. We also observe periodicity during the day due to convective cells. This is used to estimate the boundary layer height, yielding values between 2.3 and 7.7 km. A data‐science based metric is proposed to provide a quantification of the year‐to‐year differences in the wind speeds. This highlights variations linked to dust activity as well as other transient differences. On the whole, the seismic‐derived winds confirm the dominance of the global circulation leading to repeatable weather patterns. Plain Language Summary: Wind measurements made on the surface of Mars are relatively rare, but are vital to understand how the atmosphere behaves. Near‐surface winds cause dust lifting/mixing in the lower atmosphere. This is important on Mars because the atmosphere is very thin, hence dust blocks radiation from the Sun and impacts circulation. NASA's InSight mission recorded wind data for around 750 Mars days to study such effects. However, the seismometer recorded for almost 1400 sols. This seismometer recorded vibrations generated by the wind. We propose to estimate the winds based on the seismic measurements using advanced data processing to expand the wind data set. We use this data set to examine the year‐to‐year variation of the wind in terms of their daily and seasonal cycles. The fact the data set is so continuous also enables the extraction of atmospheric waves with periods of multiple sols and other phenomena such as convective cells. Finally, we propose a statistical method to quantify the year‐to‐year differences in wind speeds which highlights those due to atmospheric dust content variability as well as others for further study. These observed differences, however, are shown to be relatively minor compared to the major weather patterns which repeat from year to year. Key Points: We introduce a neural network to produce wind retrievals from the seismic data on InSightA year‐to‐year comparison confirms the consistency in the winds at InSight predominantly driven by large scale circulationSeveral transient year‐to‐year variations are linked to local atmospheric dust content and differences in baroclinic periods or phases</abstract>
  <pubTypes>Academic Journal</pubTypes>
  <an>184015203</an>
  <docTypes>Article</docTypes>
  <volume>130</volume>
  <issns>2169-9097</issns>
  <degreeLevel></degreeLevel>
  <plink>https://research.ebsco.com/linkprocessor/plink?id=88023d3c-786f-3681-bc77-2d73610bcdf2</plink>
  <doids></doids>
  <publisher>Wiley-Blackwell</publisher>
  <contributors>Stott, Alexander E. ; Garcia, Raphael F. ; Murdoch, Naomi ; Mimoun, David ; Drilleau, Mélanie ; Newman, Claire ; Spiga, Aymeric ; Banfield, Don ; Lemmon, Mark ; Navarro, Sara ; Mora‐Sotomayor, Luis ; Charalambous, Constantinos ; Pike, William T. ; Lognonné, Philippe ; Banerdt, William B.</contributors>
  <coverDate>Feb2025</coverDate>
  <longDBName>GreenFILE</longDBName>
  <doi>10.1029/2024JE008695</doi>
</record>
