<record>
  <isbns>979-8-3315-0484-7</isbns>
  <shortDBName>edseee</shortDBName>
  <isiType>GEN</isiType>
  <notes></notes>
  <mid></mid>
  <language></language>
  <source>SoutheastCon 2025, 2025, SoutheastCon</source>
  <bookEdition></bookEdition>
  <title>Enhancing Elderly Care with AI: A Review of Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning Applications</title>
  <pageEnd>905</pageEnd>
  <pageStart>900</pageStart>
  <peerReviewed>true</peerReviewed>
  <isOpenAccess></isOpenAccess>
  <publicationDate>20250322</publicationDate>
  <pageCount>6</pageCount>
  <publisherLocations></publisherLocations>
  <issue></issue>
  <identifiers></identifiers>
  <subjects>Aerospace ; Bioengineering ; Communication, Networking and Broadcast Technologies ; Components, Circuits, Devices and Systems ; Computing and Processing ; Engineered Materials, Dielectrics and Plasmas ; Engineering Profession ; Fields, Waves and Electromagnetics ; General Topics for Engineers ; Geoscience ; Nuclear Engineering ; Photonics and Electrooptics ; Power, Energy and Industry Applications ; Robotics and Control Systems ; Signal Processing and Analysis ; Transportation ; Ethics ; Privacy ; Navigation ; Decision making ; Medical services ; Machine learning ; Digital intelligence ; Older adults ; Usability ; Remote monitoring ; Caregiving ; Elderly Care ; Healthcare ; Artificial Intelligence ; Machine Learning</subjects>
  <abstract>The growing global elderly population demands efficient, personalized, and accessible healthcare solutions. Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Machine Learning (ML) have emerged as transformative tools in elderly caregiving, enhancing disease diagnostics, treatment planning, remote monitoring, and health record management. These technologies offer greater autonomy for seniors and improved efficiency for caregivers and healthcare professionals. However, barriers such as data privacy concerns, AI's opaque decision-making (black box problem), and digital literacy challenges continue to limit their widespread adoption. This review examines strategies to improve AI transparency, strengthen privacy safeguards, and develop user-friendly interfaces, ensuring that AI-driven healthcare solutions remain accessible and trustworthy for elderly individuals. Findings emphasize the need for a balanced AI-human caregiving model, where AI complements rather than replaces human caregivers, preserving the compassionate and ethical dimensions of elderly care. Addressing these challenges will enable AI to reshape elderly caregiving-bridging technological advancements with human empathy to improve healthcare outcomes and quality of life for seniors.</abstract>
  <pubTypes>Conference Paper</pubTypes>
  <an>edseee.10971504</an>
  <docTypes>Conference</docTypes>
  <volume></volume>
  <issns>1558058X</issns>
  <degreeLevel></degreeLevel>
  <plink>https://research.ebsco.com/linkprocessor/plink?id=c030d118-948a-3e0d-a82b-b2c89767397c</plink>
  <doids></doids>
  <publisher>IEEE</publisher>
  <contributors>Shrestha, Stutika Thapa ; Ghosh, Arup Kumar</contributors>
  <coverDate>20250322</coverDate>
  <longDBName>IEEE Xplore Digital Library</longDBName>
  <doi>10.1109/SoutheastCon56624.2025.10971504</doi>
</record>
