<record>
  <isbns></isbns>
  <shortDBName>eric</shortDBName>
  <isiType>JOUR</isiType>
  <notes></notes>
  <mid></mid>
  <language>eng</language>
  <source>SAGE Open</source>
  <bookEdition></bookEdition>
  <title>A Transcendental LASSO Function for Combining Machine Learning and Statistical Model Forecasts</title>
  <pageEnd></pageEnd>
  <pageStart></pageStart>
  <peerReviewed>true</peerReviewed>
  <isOpenAccess></isOpenAccess>
  <publicationDate>20240701</publicationDate>
  <pageCount></pageCount>
  <publisherLocations></publisherLocations>
  <issue>3</issue>
  <identifiers></identifiers>
  <subjects>Motor Vehicles ; Artificial Intelligence ; Prediction ; Regression (Statistics) ; Short Term Memory ; Models ; Error Patterns ; Accuracy ; Least Squares Statistics ; Supply and Demand ; Information Management ; Energy</subjects>
  <abstract>The aim of the study is the development of methodology for accurate estimation of electric vehicle demand; which is paramount regarding various aspects of the firms decision-making such as optimal price, production level, and corresponding amounts of capital and labor; as well as supply chain, inventory control, capital financing, and operational expenses management. The forecasting methods utilized include statistical techniques ("autoregressive integrated moving average" [ARIMA], and "polynomial regression"), machine learning ("nonlinear autoregressive neural network" [NAR]), "deep learning (long short-term memory [LSTM])", "hybrid and combination forecasting." With regard to the latter method, our study experiments with four different combining model approaches, including the introduction of an original, novel combining method with the employment of a transcendental LASSO function, which is used to form combinations of forecasts generated by the NAR, ARIMA, and polynomial regression models. The LASSO-based combining model proved superior to all other models, for the majority of forecast error statistics; where the root mean square error (RMSE) and mean absolute percentage error (MAPE) values are 4.5% and 8% respectively lower than the average level of the component model forecasts. The major implications of our empirical findings are that greater accuracy in demand forecasting can be achieved with a combining model approach, rather than reliance on any particular, singular model. Furthermore, given its superior performance, the employment of the studys LASSO-based combining model to forecast electric vehicle demand may lead to optimal firm decision-making over a range of organizational facets, which is predicated on accurate demand function estimation.</abstract>
  <pubTypes>Academic Journal</pubTypes>
  <an>EJ1442325</an>
  <docTypes>Journal Articles ; Reports - Research</docTypes>
  <volume>14</volume>
  <issns>2158-2440</issns>
  <degreeLevel></degreeLevel>
  <plink>https://research.ebsco.com/linkprocessor/plink?id=c101e2c2-95df-3934-b0e3-6b9f7f179075</plink>
  <doids></doids>
  <publisher></publisher>
  <contributors>Ugur Sener ; Salvatore Joseph Terregrossa</contributors>
  <coverDate>2024</coverDate>
  <longDBName>ERIC</longDBName>
  <doi>10.1177/21582440241262695</doi>
</record>
