<record>
  <isbns></isbns>
  <shortDBName>edsdoj</shortDBName>
  <isiType>GEN</isiType>
  <notes></notes>
  <mid></mid>
  <language>English</language>
  <source>Journal of Intelligent Systems</source>
  <bookEdition></bookEdition>
  <title>Application and optimization of machine learning algorithms for optical character recognition in complex scenarios</title>
  <pageEnd>84</pageEnd>
  <pageStart>161</pageStart>
  <peerReviewed>true</peerReviewed>
  <isOpenAccess></isOpenAccess>
  <publicationDate>20250301</publicationDate>
  <pageCount>-76</pageCount>
  <publisherLocations></publisherLocations>
  <issue>1</issue>
  <identifiers></identifiers>
  <subjects>automated machine learning algorithms ; artificial intelligence ; machine learning algorithms ; optical character recognition ; system implementation ; Science ; Electronic computers. Computer science ; QA75.5-76.95</subjects>
  <abstract>In the era of artificial intelligence, the technology of optical character recognition under complex backgrounds has become particularly important. This article investigated how machine learning algorithms can improve the accuracy of text recognition in complex scenarios. By analyzing algorithms such as scale-invariant feature transform, K-means clustering, and support vector machine, a system was constructed to address the challenges of text recognition under complex backgrounds. Experimental results show that the proposed algorithm achieves 7.66% higher accuracy than traditional algorithms, and the built system is fast, powerful, and highly satisfactory to users, with a 13.6% difference in results between the two groups using different methods. This indicates that the method proposed in this study can effectively meet the needs of complex text recognition, significantly improving recognition efficiency and user satisfaction.</abstract>
  <pubTypes>Academic Journal</pubTypes>
  <an>edsdoj.47560732592341999a0ecb973107880b</an>
  <docTypes>article</docTypes>
  <volume>34</volume>
  <issns>2191026X</issns>
  <degreeLevel></degreeLevel>
  <plink>https://research.ebsco.com/linkprocessor/plink?id=fcd33d10-08d9-380e-b596-260bceba7c88</plink>
  <doids></doids>
  <publisher>De Gruyter</publisher>
  <contributors>Liu Liming ; Yang Dexin ; Chen Juntao</contributors>
  <coverDate>2025</coverDate>
  <longDBName>Directory of Open Access Journals</longDBName>
  <doi>10.1515/jisys-2023-0307</doi>
</record>
